

AAMIR MUHAMMAD

Software Developer

CONTACT

- (+49) 1781667811
- aamirmuhammad91@gmail.com
- Fontainstr. 9, 30519 Hannover
- in linkedin.com/aamir
- Github Profile
- Portfolio

EDUCATION

2018 - 2021

FRANKFURT UNIVERSITY OF APPLIED SCIENCES, FRANKFURT AM MAIN

Master of Engineering in IT

• 2008 - 2012

NWFP UNIVERSITY OF ENGINEERING & TECHNOLOGY PESHAWAR

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

SKILLS

- Teamwork
- Effective Communication
- Critical Thinking
- Quick Learner
- Public Relations

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- German (Intermediate)
- Urdu (Native)

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a full-stack web developer with over 4 years of experience in application development. Currently, I work with the Data Science and Digital Libraries Research Group on the Terminology Service project, where we have developed tools for Ontology Mappings, Semantic Search, and Annotation Services.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | MAR 2022 - PRESENT

Leibniz Information Center for Science & Technology (TIB)

- Developed Semantic Search tool using Python, React.js.
- Built 40% of the frontend for the TIB Terminology Service.
- Created CI/CD pipelines for NFDI4ING deployments.
- Integrated TIB search API with Dataverse for metadata.
- Assisted in developing Annotation Service and Mapping Tool
- Ingest ontologies to the TIB Terminology Service.

STUDENT ASSISTANT | SEP 2019 - DEC 2021

Deutsche Börse Group, Frankfurt am Main, Germany

- To support business and IT departments.
- Answering calls and opening tickets / interactions.
- Support the Technical Key Account Manager in their daily work.
- Help with projects in the field of service management.
- Maintenance of data in SAP CRM.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER | JAN 2017 - AUG 2018

JZZ the I.T Solution (Pakistan)

- Built responsive web pages compatible across devices.
- Developed and maintained web services and APIs.
- Created reusable React components for dynamic Uls.

FIELD SERVICE ENGINEER | MAR 2014 - DEC 2016

Alsawary Trading Co. LLC (Dubai)

- Diagnosis of machinery problems.
- Resolve malfunctions or other crises when they arise.
- Overseas repairs and technical improvements.
- Install new systems and technology.
- Inspect and test material and machinery for safety.
- Draft and submit reports.

HOBBIES

- Jogging
- Table Tennis
- Chess

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming languages: JavaScript, Python, Java
- JavaScript Framework and Libraries: React.js, jQuery, ES6, Redux Toolkit
- Java Framework and Libraries: Spring Boot
- TypeScript: TypeScript
- Design: CSS, Bootstrap, Material-UI
- API integration: RESTful APIs, JSON, XML
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Development tools: IntelliJ IDEA, Visual Studio Code
- Client Operating Systems: Linux Mint, Windows
- Servers: Debian Servers (Bullseye, Bookworms)
- Version Control and Collaboration Tools: Git, GitHub, GitLab, Confluence, Markdown
- Other Tools and Technologies: Ansible, Dockers, Docker compose, CI/CD pipelines

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Master Thesis "Sensor Application for Autonomous Illumination Control"
- Differentiate between the time signals using Convolutional neural Networks
- Network Slicing in an Emulated Network Environment
- IoT Smart Home Entry Authorization
- Differentiate among Human, wall and car using Red Pitaya
- Implementation of Save, Test and Load methods for Machine Learning Algorithms
- Bachelor Thesis "Implementation of dynamic channel assignment scheme for Wireless Mesh Networks".
- Design a calculator using 8051 microcontrollers.

COMMUNITY PROJECTS

- Created a desktop application for a public school in Pakistan using React and Electron.js. The application streamlined data management and enabled efficient search and retrieval of student information.
- Worked with a website development team for Ummat Welfare Trust, a social and welfare organization in Pakistan, contributing to their online presence and community outreach efforts.